Pitch, sound. Let's transition from song to speech. Interestingly, languages are
spoken at different pitches, so it's important to recognize the pitch you're
coming from as well as the pitch you're heading toward. Even though there are
millions of English speakers, both male and female, there's a general pitch range
into which English falls. Listen to this audio clip, ranging from a Japanese woman
speaking at a very high pitch to an Arabic man speaking in a much deeper register.
You'll notice that English is in the middle. In Spanish, this is the sound of
the Spanish. This is the Swedish sound. This is the German language. This is the
Norwegian language. This is the French sound. This is the American sound. This is
the Danish language. This is the Russian sound. This is the Turkish language. This
is the Arabic language. Generally speaking, to Americans, a higher pitch
indicates stress or tension, and they will respond accordingly, even if you're not
stressed. Of course, speaking in a second language can be stressful, to match your
speaking voice in English to your deepest voice in your own language.